<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Files on Thumbs</title>
    <link>https://125837492739.github.io/files/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Files on Thumbs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>no@no.com (Christopher Zhang)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>no@no.com (Christopher Zhang)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Christopher Zhang</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://125837492739.github.io/files/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy</title>
      <link>https://125837492739.github.io/files/lenses/anatomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>no@no.com (Christopher Zhang)</author>
      <guid>https://125837492739.github.io/files/lenses/anatomy/</guid>
      <description>What is the bone structure of the thumb? The thumb has two bones (phalanges), meaning one joint. The thumb interphalangeal (IP) joint is similar to the distal interphalangeal (DIP) joint in the other fingers, both being the closest to the tip of the finger. The Metacarpophalangeal Joint (MP) is where the metacarpal (palm bones) meets the finger bones. The MP joint allows for us to bend the thumb, and is important for pinching and gripping things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemistry Of Life</title>
      <link>https://125837492739.github.io/files/lenses/chemistry-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>no@no.com (Christopher Zhang)</author>
      <guid>https://125837492739.github.io/files/lenses/chemistry-of-life/</guid>
      <description>How do macromolecules affect the production of human thumbs? The thumb is not a normal digit. It is the last digit to form and is the most commonly affected when limb disruption happens. It is defined by the overlapping of the HOXA13, TBX5, GLI3R, and HOXD13 transcription factors, without other HOXD transcription factors. (I will explain this later.)&#xA;Because it is the last digit to form, the thumb has a greater risk of disruption, with over 1100 syndromes listed in the OMIM database.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution</title>
      <link>https://125837492739.github.io/files/lenses/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>no@no.com (Christopher Zhang)</author>
      <guid>https://125837492739.github.io/files/lenses/evolution/</guid>
      <description>How did we evolve to have longer and stronger opposable thumbs? For many millions of years, animals have had partially opposable thumbs. They had short thumbs and long fingers to swing on branches, since longer thumbs would get in the way.&#xA;Recent research suggests that opposable thumbs as flexible and strong as ours evolved approximately 2 million years ago. Shorter thumbs and longer fingers are good for climbing, but our ancestors stopped living in the trees and started making tools more often.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genetics</title>
      <link>https://125837492739.github.io/files/lenses/genetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>no@no.com (Christopher Zhang)</author>
      <guid>https://125837492739.github.io/files/lenses/genetics/</guid>
      <description>What are some traits in thumbs that can be passed down from parent to child? A trait that is passed down from parent to child is the hitchhiker&amp;#39;s thumb.&#xA;Hitchhiker&amp;#39;s thumb is a trait in human thumbs that allows people to bend their thumbs back further than being straight (picture below).&#xA;While it is often regarded as a simple Mendelian trait, it is not actually that simple, as we will see below.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://125837492739.github.io/files/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>no@no.com (Christopher Zhang)</author>
      <guid>https://125837492739.github.io/files/glossary/</guid>
      <description> Reproductive Success This is how well they can reproduce&#xA;1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Membranes And Transport</title>
      <link>https://125837492739.github.io/files/lenses/membranes-and-transport/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>no@no.com (Christopher Zhang)</author>
      <guid>https://125837492739.github.io/files/lenses/membranes-and-transport/</guid>
      <description>How do gradients and diffusion play a role in the movement of thumbs? The movement of the thumb, like other muscles in the body, is influenced by gradients and diffusion. One of the molecules involved in this process is the calcium ion. As I explained in the chemistry of life lens, muscle fibers are made up of sarcomeres, and are triggered to contract by calcium ions.&#xA;When you want to move your thumb, nerve impulses cause calcium channels to open.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
